Leah: The KISS Principle is a term that
is widely used in a variety of different
industries so let’s look at what it
means especially in relation to coding.
KISS is an acronym for a design principle
noted by the US Navy in 1960 and it stands
for ‘Keep it Simple and Straightforward’
and covers many different areas of design
including engineering and programming.
There are other variations of this
including ‘keep it short and simple’
and ‘keep it simple, stupid’.
Whatever way it is used
it means the same thing.
Jack: ‘Keep it simple stupid’ or
even ‘keep it stupid simple’ are
most commonly used in programming.
By keeping the programming simple,
service and maintenance are much
easier and there are no hard and fast
rules regarding the implementation
of code, only that it should be
simple and therefore easily modified.
There are many reasons for
implementing this philosophy.
It may prevent you from wasting time and
effort developing complicated protocols
which take a long time to write.
However, the primary benefits,
are for those that may use
the software afterwards.
This could include both other
programmers and customers who want
a product which is simple to use.
For example, you might
subscribe to the concept of a
‘minimal viable product’ [MVP].
This is where you aim to provide
the simplest product which will
fulfil the required criteria.